# Jim C. Goldbloom GoldTechPro LLC

#### Web Developer

jim@goldtechpro.com http://www.goldtechpro.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/jimgoldbloom

3810 Laramie Place Apt. E Alexandria, VA 22309 Phone: (703) 258-5413

#### SUMMARY

Over 15 years experienced senior level IT professional skilled in front and back end development layers of the Internet web technology stack, specializing in open source technologies including LAMP and the Drupal based Content Management System (CMS). My roles include primary content provider, custom theme and module developer and team leader for crucial portal projects. Excellent communication skills allow me to interface with stakeholders, either technical or lay oriented and via individual or group training, to accurately identify and meet the needs of the client and their end users. I run and maintain my own IT consulting firm, GoldTechPro LLC.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES & SKILLS**

- \* XHTML 1.0. XML/XSL 1.0. HTML 5. CSS 2/3. JavaScript/DHTML. Aiax. JSON
- \* LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) including XAMP/MAMP Pro for Windows/Mac
- \* PHP 5 OOP (Object Oriented Programming, open source class development)
- \* MvSQL 5 database
- \* Oracle 10/11G database
- \* JavaScript open source frameworks (jQuery and Agile Toolkit/MVC, MooTools, Script.aculo.us)
- \* Drupal 6 and 7 Content Management Systems, advanced theme, module and API development
- \* Social Networking rich web 2.0 mashups including Facebook, Twitter, ShareThis and Google Custom Search API's, Atomz PDF Search
- \* Apache Solr/Drupal search integration, Word Press, phpBB and vBulletin forum software, 123 FlashChat live chat
- \* RSS news feed resource syndication (XML/RDF 1.0, RSS 2.0/Atom implementation)
- \* Linux system administration including custom shell scripts, crontab, IPTables local firewall setup, daemon installation (RPM, YUM, direct binary source compiling x386 or x64)
- \* VM Ware virtual server guest setup and host configuration
- \* Macromedia DreamWeaver MX Studio IDE, Aptana Stuido, Zend Studio
- \* Drush, SVN for local sandbox development and version control for Drupal or other CMS
- \* Adobe Photoshop CS3, Fireworks graphic format creation/editing tools
- \* SpamAssassin, Procmail and virtual mail mapping/alias/DNS setup, SSH/FTP access

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Strayer University - Arlington Campus, Virginia

**Graduated 2003** 

- \* Computer Information Systems, Diploma in Web Development, 2001-2003
- \* Accredited Diploma providing highly focused academic work in a specific technical area

Accolades: President's List Honoree GPA: 4.0

Jim C. Goldbloom (703) 258-5413

#### **RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Navigation Arts - McLean, Virginia

June 2011-Dec 2011

Drupal Developer (Full time, In-House)

<a href="http://www.gpfi.org">http://www.gpfi.org</a> (IFC, Global Partnership for Financial Inclusion site)
<a href="http://www.smefinanceforum.org">http://www.smefinanceforum.org</a> (IFC, Small and Medium Enterprises Finance Forum site)
<a href="http://www.nmwa.org">http://www.nmwa.org</a> (National Museum of Women in the Arts site)

Blog: http://blog.navigationarts.com/drupal-7-a-coming-of-age-story/ (Drupal 7: Coming of Age)

- \* Drupal back end web development including application development, server configuration and Content Management System integration and customization
- \* Translated design comps and wireframes into a system of flexible and reusable code templates while maintaining an extreme attention to detail for concurrent projects
- \* Collaborated with team members to determine the best solution for client and user needs
- \* Developed and delivered production-ready code and supporting documentation in a timely manner with high quality results
- \* Communicated and collaborated with the project manager, engineers, designers, and site authors in all stages of production
- \* Delivered on multiple projects at once while adequately managing individual schedules and work quality
- \* Drupal, LAMP support and technical liaison for all Navigation Arts departments

## **Web Development Special Projects**

- \* Assisted IFC with security remediation for two major sites to pass a comprehensive security scan required by the client's SOC/NOC
- \* Worked with Quality Assurance Test Architect to modernize and standardize the Drupal CMS Specifications template to streamline work flow and optimize the QA testing procedure within the Tracker application

## **Related Training**

\* Washington D.C. Drupal Intermediate Training – July 21, 2011 Phase 2 Technologies, Alexandria Virginia

"As a project manager, I relied on his time estimates as well as his meticulous attention to detail. His delivery was consistent and his work product was outstanding, much to the delight of his entire team." – Michael Heckman, PM

Jim C. Goldbloom (703) 258-5413

## Ace Info Solutions, Inc. - McLean, Virginia

May 2004-Jan 2011

Web Developer / LAMP / Drupal Developer

Contract: Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA) Job Site: Department of Commerce, Washington, D.C.

http://www.mbda.gov (web portal)

http://www.medweek.gov (third party hosted)

http://partnernet.mbda.gov (social networking within the agency and it's Funded Centers)

- \* Senior Web Developer for all agency web sites including site design, application development, server configuration and Content Management System integration
- \* Team Leader overseeing projects involving Junior Web Developer, Content Manager, Network Engineer and associated stakeholders
- \* LAMP/VM Ware based web server administration and security protocols
- \* Work closely with Business Analysts and other developers and stakeholders within the agency's operating business units
- \* Analyze requirements and provide recommended technical design solutions that are efficient, scalable and maintainable via the SDLC and in-house version control system
- \* Provide training, documentation and technical support for individual or group presentation

## **Web Development Special Projects**

- \* Reboot of the agency web portal (2010) full integration of Drupal CMS including custom themes and module development into legacy infrastructure (PHP/MySQL, CF/Oracle)
- \* Introduced social networking and Rich Web 2.0 mashups to the web technology stack for all web sites including RSS, Facebook, Twitter, Share This, You Tube and Word Press
- \* LDAP authentication and employee directory module for Drupal
- \* Linux security hardening project resolved critical security issues all MBDA Linux servers
- \* Implemented the agency's third party hosted MED Week web site managed remote configuration and security hardening of the LAMP setup and Drupal configuration
- \* Design, build and implementation of PartnerNet web site for MBDA staff and funded centers with emphasis on social networking mashups and Communities of Practice
- \* Event Registration Application a calendar driven, PHP/CF/Oracle web application with checkin, checkout interface and reports generation engine
- \* Media Gallery an audio/video/document repository web application with advanced gallery features integrated with RSS syndication and iTunes Podcasting
- \* MBDA Community Exchange a seamless integration of the popular open source phpBB forum software with bridged user database
- \* Dynamic custom content approval system (prior to reboot) time sensitive content submissions follow multi-level approval/rejection process flow, incoming queues, E-Mail notifications and logging
- \* Custom search engine web application and template system with search index generated via crontab spider crawl and ranked/paginated results including optional topic highlighting
- \* Fully integrated custom PHP error handler with detailed error logging for administrators and E-Mail reporting tools and sensible controls to prevent looping
- \* Searchable and interactive knowledge base (Frequently Asked Questions) a user submitted/staff approved Q&A and polls web application
- \* Contract Tracking Database a custom built staff accessible web application written in PHP/MySQL storing client supplied contracting opportunities following Hurricane Katrina in 2004

Jim C. Goldbloom (703) 258-5413

## Computer-Help, Inc. / Unisys - Crystal City, Virginia

Sep 2002-Nov 2002

Help Desk Technician, Junior Web Developer Contract: 90 days

http://gsaauctions.gov (General Services Administration web site)

- \* Team Lead, Help Desk Established new Help Desk organizational infrastructure
- \* Interview, hire and train initial Help Desk team members
- \* Design Web based solutions as applicable and maintain content at gsaauctions.gov

## **Web Development Special Projects**

\* Designed and implemented a custom trouble ticket tracking web application in PHP/MySQL

## NTT/Verio, Inc. - Springfield, Virginia

Oct 1997-Feb 2002

Customer Engineer (CE) Level 2 - Quality Assurance

- \* Sole Quality Assurance for CE Technical Support and all national on-call escalations.
- \* Level 2 Technical Support, selected to the first national Network Operations Center (NOC) oncall team uniquely identified as "CE Technical Support".
- \* Level 1 client side Personal Web page setup, E-Mail, DNS and related zone setup.
- \* Primary technical liaison between sales and network engineering and the national Customer Service Organization (CSO) for all support and broadband WAN installations.

# Monumental Network Systems - Chantilly, Virginia

Nov 1996-Oct 1997

Sales Engineer, Technical Support (Company was acquired by Verio, Inc. in 1997)

- \* Develop intranet Web site to serve as repository for support related tutorial files.
- \* Technical contact and advisor for sales representatives and agents, pre-contract.
- \* Dialup and dedicated access daytime technical support (PPP, ISDN, DS1, DS3).
- \* On-call support within Network Operations Center (NOC duty)

#### **Web Development Special Projects**

- \* Designed intranet Web site to document escalation procedures adopted nationally.
- \* Developed intranet Web site to configure and quality check all access WAN related DNS.

## **Groups and Organizations**

Member and presenter, Drupal4Gov – Drupal Project Planning, i.e. documentation and discussion to help agencies new to Drupal get started. http://drupal4gov.betaspaces.com/members

## **Unique Recognition**

"Above and Beyond Award" (Indyne, 2004) engraved:

"We hereby express our sincere appreciation to Jim Goldbloom in grateful recognition of your outstanding performance, team spirit, and commitment to excellence."

#### **ADDITIONAL REFERENCES**

"Jim maintained a positive attitude in the face of challenging demands from the client. Jim consistently put in the extra time and effort needed to achieve excellent results. In short, he is a consummate development professional with whom I would gladly work again." – Michael Heckman, Project Manager, Navigation Arts

"Jim is always there and consistently exceeds our expectations with his designs and innovative solutions. He was instrumental on many occasions for publishing our MedWeek wite leading to increased participants at that event. He is very reliable and does not hesitate to devote extra time and resources to ensure we are the best in class." – Yolanda Whitley, Chief Information Officer, Minority Business Development Agency

"He demonstrated a high level of creativity, professionalism, customer service and knowledge of web tools that best support the needs of the agency. Mr. Goldbloom communicated with my team and others effectively and demonstrated a high passion in advising and helping staff with technology solutions. PartnerNet was developed successfully and at a very low cost for the agency, thanks to Mr. Goldbloom's knowledge of Drupal..." – Ivonne Cunarro, Chief Knowledge Officer, Research and Knowledge Management, Minority Business Development Agency

"As a Director of Verio Customer Engineering, I watched Jim play a leadership role in writing system tools and scripts for the department. As a programmer, he is very thorough in his documentation and his work products." - Andy Peterson, NTT/Verio, Inc.

"Jim distinguished himself among his peers by developing tools and processes that consistently exceeded the expectations of my self and of my directors. Solutions that he created were imaginative and efficient and they positively impacted our internal operations and our service to our customers." - Craig Harlow, Manager, Customer Engineer, NTT/Verio, Inc.

Additional letters of recommendation are available upon request.